Guide to the Anne Firor Scott papers, 1963-2002
Duke University. University Archives
Anne Firor Scott papers 1963-2002
Duke University. University Archives
Scott, Anne Firor, 1921-
6 linear feet Extent: 6000 Items
Anne Firor Scott taught in the History Dept. at Duke University from 1961-1991. She is currently W. K. Boyd Professor of History Emerita. The collection includes correspondence, subject files, and student papers and a videorecording. Most of the collection is restricted. It ranges in date from 1963-2002.
UA.29.02.0134
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Anne Firor Scott papers were received by the University Archives as transfers from 1964-2004.
Biographical Note
Anne Firor Scott was born April 24, 1921 in Montezuma Georgia. She married Andrew MacKay Scott in 1947. She graduated summa cum laude in 1941 from the University of Georgia and earned her M.A. at Northwestern in 1944 and her Ph.D. in 1958 at Radcliffe College. From 1944-1947 and again from 1951-1953, Scott served as a research associate, congressional representative and editor of THE NATIONAL VOTER for the League of Women Voters of the United States. She began teaching at Duke University in 1961 as an Assistant Professor in History and in 1980 was promoted to W. K. Boyd Professor of History and served as such until 1991 when she retired as Professor Emerita.
Collection Overview
Collection contains correspondence, student papers, and committee records. Some materials relate to University matters, but most concern the study and teaching of American history, particularly the history of women in the South. Included are 24 students' reactions to the assassination of John F. Kennedy (1963), 17 student papers on the nuclear accident at Three Mile Island (1979), a "Last Lecture" by Dr. Scott ("A Modest Proposal for a Quiet Revolution," 1966), 170 students' interviews with working women (1976), and a letter by Ruth Dozier describing the work of a home demonstration agent in North Carolina from 1900-1920. All of these materials are open for research. University-related material includes the University Scholar Teacher Award (1982-1983) [restricted] and included a files on the Provost Search Committee (1982-1983) which was removed by Archives staff. Correspondence is sometimes labeled Business Correspondence and sometimes as AFS Chronological File. The topical or subject files include letters of recommendation, History Department minutes, and files relating to seminars, meetings, publishing, and professional associations. The correspondence and subject files are closed except by permission of Dr. Scott and the University Archivist. The material ranges in date from 1963-2002.
Subject Headings
Scott, Anne Firor, 1921-; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. Dept. of History -- Faculty; Women -- United States -- History; Education, Higher -- North Carolina; Women historians -- United States; History -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant (Pa.)
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004
Duke University Archives
Biographical Reference Collection, 1972-2004
Duke University Archives
Photograph Collection, 1861-2006
Duke University Archives
Anne Firor Scott Papers, 1939-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John William Firor Papers, 1860-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - AFS Chronological File I (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, beginning 1974 June (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1974 January (Box 1)
  - Current Correspondence, 1973 Fall (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 December (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1973 Summer-1973 November (Box 1)
  - Current, 1973 May-June (Box 1)
  - Professorial Correspondence, 1972 July-1973 April (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1972 July (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1972 January-June (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Professorial Correspondence: Inactive (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1971 August-December (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1971 June-August (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Business Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Chronological File, 1985 January (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1984 January (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1983 January-June (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1982 July-December (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1982 January-June (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence File, from 1980 February (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence File, until 1980 February (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, beginning 1979 November 1 (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, beginning 1979 June (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1979 January-undated (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1978 June-December (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1977 December-1978 May (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, 1977 September-undated (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, beginning 1977 March 1 (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, beginning 1976 December (Box 2)
  - Chronological File, beginning 1976 Summer (Box 2)
  - Chronological File (IV), beginning 1976 January (Box 2)
  - Chronological File (III), 1975-1976 Summer (Box 2)
  - Student Essays Re: Kennedy Assassination, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission (Box 3)
  - Faculty Discussion Group (Box 3)
  - TIAA: Letters of Protest (Box 3)
  - Law Record Newsletters, 1971 (Box 3)
  - USSR (Box 3)
  - USSR Colloquium (Box 3)
  - Hobart and William Smith-Evaluation of History Department (Box 3)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 3)
  - Sacred Journeys- Reviews for NET, 1976-1980 (Box 3)
  - University Scholar/Teacher, 1983 (Box 3)
  - History, Department of; Records, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Executive Committee, 1974 September-1980 September (Box 3)
  - Trinity College Historical Society, 1974-1981 (Box 3)
  - TCHS, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Trinity College Historical Society, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Anne F. Scott: Speeches (Box 3)
  - Distinguished Professors, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Duke Women, 1989 March (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Anne F. Scott Speeches (Box 3)
  - Julia Spruill Prize (Box 3)
  - University of Toronto, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 3)
  - Comment on What Happened to the Chesnut Diaries, 1979 April 15 (OAH) (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 3)
  - Margaret Jarman Hagood (AFS work on her for NAW) (Box 3)
  - History of Education Quarterly (Box 3)
  - Emma LeConte (Box 3)
  - Radcliffe Graduate Medal (Box 3)
  - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities (Box 3)
  - Williams College Visiting Committee (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1985 November 1 (Box 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence, beginning 1985 December 19 (Box 3)
  - Bogue Introduction (Box 4)
  - Southern Historical Assn-Introduction of Louis Harlan (Box 4)
  - Supplement to NAW, 1976-1980 (Box 4)
  - 1960s Student Activism (Box 4)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 4)
  - National Humanities Center Board (Box 4)
  - AFS Academic Council (Box 4)
  - China Trip, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Australians (Box 4)
  - Duke University Last Lecture, 1966 April 20 (Box 4)
  - Last Lecture: Response (Box 4)
  - An Address to the Board of Trustees of Duke University, 1979 May 5 (Box 4)
  - ABC Clip Introduction, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 4)
  - Harbison Award Application, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Margaret Harper: Campaign, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Houghton Mifflin Book on Women in America (correspondence), 1968-1976 (Box 4)
  - Johns Hopkins Appointment, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - TIAA Nominating Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 4)
  - Women's History Sources Survey, Chambers-Hindig Project (Box 4)
  - SNPA Seminar, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Women scholars and requests for names (Box 4)
  - Scholars of Women's History, raw data (Box 4)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Proposal (Box 4)
  - Duke Symposium, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Coalition for Women's Higher Education (Box 4)
  - Citizens Advisory Council on the Status of Women (Box 4)
  - AHA Panel, 1970 December (Box 4)
  - Teacher-Course Evaluation- Hist. 124 (Box 4)
  - The Southern Lady: Reviews and correspondence (Box 4)
  - Frederick Jackson Turner Award (Box 4)
  - Scope and nature of OAH (Box 4)
  - OAH Treasurer Search (Box 4)
  - Program (Box 4)
  - National Coordinating Committee (Box 4)
  - Executive Secretary (Box 4)
  - Organization of American Historians (OAH): President's File (Box 4)
  - OAH Program (Box 4)
  - OAH Executive Board (Box 4)
  - OAH Essentials (Box 4)
  - Faculty (Box 4)
  - Committee Acceptances (Box 4)
  - Confidential File (Box 4)
  - Interviews with Working Women, History 170, 1976 Spring (Box 4)
  - Student Papers: Artis, JE, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Student Papers: Infosino, J.M., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Student Papers: Fishman, Aleisa. Three Generations of Women. History 170, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Student Papers: Ginsberg, Marnie S. Three Generations… History 170, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Student Work- Three Mile Island (Box 4)
  - Dozier, Ruth E., 1974 (Box 4)
  - Student Work- Why I Am in College (Box 4)
  - Chronological File, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Women Activists in Black and White, 2002 (Videotape Tape Shelf, Box 4)